<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Savecraft</name>
  <author>joshsymonds</author>
  <packageId>savecraft.rimworld</packageId>
  <url>https://savecraft.gg</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.5</li>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <!-- In-game description uses Unity Rich Text (XML-escaped angle brackets).
       Steam Workshop description uses BBCode, set separately via web editor. -->
  <description>Your AI is making things up about your colony. Savecraft fixes that.

Savecraft connects your colony to Claude and ChatGPT. Colonists, mood, resources, research, defenses, rooms, factions, threats -- real data from your actual save, updated live.

&lt;size=24&gt;What it does&lt;/size&gt;

On every save, Savecraft reads your colony state and sends it to your AI:

  • Every colonist: backstory, traits, skills, passions, mood with all modifiers, health, equipment
  • Resources: full stockpile inventory, food supply in nutrition-days, medicine by type
  • Research: current project with progress, completed techs, available projects
  • Mood and health reports: break risk, worst modifiers, injuries, diseases, immunity
  • Infrastructure: power grid, growing zones, room quality, defenses
  • World: faction relations, raid threat level, recent incidents, animals

Your AI also gets &lt;b&gt;reference modules&lt;/b&gt; that know RimWorld's actual formulas:

  • Surgery success calculator (skill, bed, medicine, lighting)
  • Crop optimizer (nutrition/day and silver/day per soil)
  • Combat calculator (ranged and melee DPS, accuracy at distance)
  • Material lookup (final stats at any quality)
  • Drug production economics and addiction risk
  • Raid point estimator from colony wealth
  • Gene builder with conflict detection
  • Research navigator with time estimates

&lt;size=24&gt;Setup&lt;/size&gt;

1. Enable this mod
2. Start a game. A link code appears automatically.
3. Enter the code at savecraft.gg
4. Add the Savecraft integration in Claude or ChatGPT
5. Ask about your colony

&lt;size=18&gt;Compatibility&lt;/size&gt;
RimWorld 1.5 and 1.6, all DLCs. Safe to add or remove mid-save. One Harmony patch (GameDataSaveLoader.SaveGame), works alongside other mods. Modded content not yet parsed.

&lt;size=18&gt;Privacy&lt;/size&gt;
Sends structured game state to Savecraft's server for your AI to read. No save files, no filesystem paths, no personal data. Open source.

https://savecraft.gg
https://github.com/joshsymonds/savecraft.gg
https://discord.gg/YnC8stpEmF</description>
</ModMetaData>
