<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Savecraft</name>
  <author>joshsymonds</author>
  <packageId>savecraft.rimworld</packageId>
  <url>https://savecraft.gg</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.5</li>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <!-- In-game description uses Unity Rich Text (XML-escaped angle brackets).
       Steam Workshop description uses BBCode, set separately via web editor. -->
  <description>Your AI is making things up about your colony. Savecraft fixes that.

Savecraft connects your colony to Claude and ChatGPT. Colonists, mood, resources, research, defenses, rooms, factions, threats. Real data from your actual save, updated live. No more invented stats.

&lt;size=24&gt;What it does&lt;/size&gt;

On every save, Savecraft reads your colony state and sends it to your AI. Every colonist with their full backstory, skills, mood modifiers, health, and gear. Your stockpile, power grid, growing zones, room quality, faction relations, raid threat level. 14 sections of structured data, not a screenshot or a summary.

Your AI also gets &lt;b&gt;reference modules&lt;/b&gt; that know RimWorld's actual formulas. Surgery success chances. Crop yield per tile. Ranged and melee DPS. Material stats at quality. Drug production economics. Raid point scaling. Gene complexity budgets. Research prerequisite chains with time estimates. Real math, not vibes.

&lt;size=24&gt;Setup&lt;/size&gt;

1. Enable this mod
2. Start a game. A link code appears automatically.
3. Enter the code at savecraft.gg
4. Add the Savecraft integration in Claude or ChatGPT
5. Ask about your colony

&lt;size=24&gt;Compatibility&lt;/size&gt;

RimWorld 1.5 and 1.6. All DLCs. Safe to add or remove mid-save. One Harmony patch on GameDataSaveLoader.SaveGame, no conflicts. Works alongside other mods. Modded content not yet parsed.

&lt;size=24&gt;Privacy&lt;/size&gt;

Savecraft sends structured game state (colonist stats, resources, research) to its server. No save files, no filesystem paths, no personal data. Fully open source.

https://savecraft.gg
https://github.com/joshsymonds/savecraft.gg
https://discord.gg/savecraft</description>
</ModMetaData>
