<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Savecraft</name>
  <author>joshsymonds</author>
  <packageId>savecraft.rimworld</packageId>
  <url>https://savecraft.gg</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.5</li>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <!-- In-game description uses Unity Rich Text (angle-bracket tags).
       Steam Workshop description uses BBCode and must be set separately
       via the Steam web editor after uploading. -->
  <description>Your AI is making things up about your colony. Savecraft fixes that.

This mod connects your colony to Claude and ChatGPT so they can see your actual game state — colonists, skills, mood, resources, research, defenses, and more. Real data, updated on every save. No more invented stats or wrong advice.

&lt;size=24&gt;What your AI sees&lt;/size&gt;

  &lt;b&gt;Colony overview&lt;/b&gt; — wealth, storyteller, difficulty, date, colonist count
  &lt;b&gt;Every colonist&lt;/b&gt; — backstory, traits, skills, mood, health, equipment
  &lt;b&gt;Resources&lt;/b&gt; — full stockpile, food supply in nutrition-days, medicine
  &lt;b&gt;Research&lt;/b&gt; — current project, completed list, available by tech level
  &lt;b&gt;Mood report&lt;/b&gt; — break thresholds, risk levels, modifiers per colonist
  &lt;b&gt;Health report&lt;/b&gt; — injuries, diseases, immunity, bleeding, pain
  &lt;b&gt;Skills and work&lt;/b&gt; — priorities, passions, incapable-of flags
  &lt;b&gt;Power grid&lt;/b&gt; — generators, batteries, consumption, surplus/deficit
  &lt;b&gt;Farming&lt;/b&gt; — growing zones, crop progress, yield, soil fertility
  &lt;b&gt;Defenses&lt;/b&gt; — turrets, traps, wall materials and counts
  &lt;b&gt;Rooms&lt;/b&gt; — role, temperature, impressiveness, beauty, cleanliness
  &lt;b&gt;Factions&lt;/b&gt; — relations, goodwill, hostile status
  &lt;b&gt;Threats&lt;/b&gt; — wealth-based raid points, recent incidents
  &lt;b&gt;Animals&lt;/b&gt; — species, bonded colonist, training, pregnancy

&lt;size=24&gt;Reference modules&lt;/size&gt;

Your AI also gets computation tools that know RimWorld's actual formulas:

  &lt;b&gt;Surgery calculator&lt;/b&gt; — success chance from skill, bed, medicine, lighting
  &lt;b&gt;Crop optimizer&lt;/b&gt; — nutrition/day and silver/day per crop-soil combo
  &lt;b&gt;Combat calculator&lt;/b&gt; — ranged and melee DPS, accuracy, armor penetration
  &lt;b&gt;Material lookup&lt;/b&gt; — final stats for any item-material-quality combo
  &lt;b&gt;Drug analyzer&lt;/b&gt; — production silver/day, addiction risk, safe intervals
  &lt;b&gt;Raid estimator&lt;/b&gt; — expected raid points from wealth and colonist count
  &lt;b&gt;Gene builder&lt;/b&gt; — xenogerm validation, complexity/metabolism budgets
  &lt;b&gt;Research navigator&lt;/b&gt; — prerequisite chains, costs, speed estimates

&lt;size=24&gt;How it works&lt;/size&gt;

1. Subscribe to this mod and enable it
2. Start a game — the mod registers and shows a link code
3. Enter the code at savecraft.gg to connect your colony
4. Add the Savecraft MCP integration in Claude or ChatGPT
5. Ask about your colony — your AI sees your actual game state

Data syncs on every save. No save files leave your machine — only parsed data.

&lt;size=24&gt;Compatibility&lt;/size&gt;

  RimWorld 1.5 and 1.6
  All DLCs supported (Royalty, Ideology, Biotech, Anomaly)
  Safe to add or remove mid-save
  No Harmony conflicts — patches only GameDataSaveLoader.SaveGame
  Works alongside other mods (modded content not yet parsed)

&lt;size=24&gt;Privacy&lt;/size&gt;

Savecraft sends structured game state to its server for your AI to read. No save files, no filesystem paths, no personal data. Open source: https://github.com/joshsymonds/savecraft.gg

&lt;size=24&gt;Links&lt;/size&gt;

  Website: https://savecraft.gg
  Source: https://github.com/joshsymonds/savecraft.gg
  Discord: https://discord.gg/savecraft</description>
</ModMetaData>
